supr.com 2019-11-17

# [EN] Privacy Policy - SUPR

Wirecard Technologies GmbH (“Wirecard” or “we”) takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. The following statement describes what personal data will be collected and processed when you visit and use the SUPR platform and/or the SUPR network of Wirecard.

### **I. GENERAL INFORMATION**

We shall collect, process and store your data in compliance with the relevant data protection laws and other relevant provisions under data protection law. The service provider for the SUPR platform is: **Wirecard Technologies GmbH  ** Einsteinring 35 85609 Aschheim Wirecard’s external corporate data protection officer is: Dr. Felix Wittern, Fieldfisher (Germany) LLP, Am Sandtorkai 68, 20457 Hamburg Wirecard‘s external corporate data protection officer is: Dr. Felix Wittern, Fieldfisher (Germany) LLP, Am Sandtorkai 68, 20457 Hamburg If you have any questions regarding the processing of your personal data or regarding data protection at Wirecard, please contact us through <https://www.wirecard.com/de/datenschutzbestimmungen/formular>. The legal responsibility for the collection and processing of data within the framework of the respective online shop on SUPR will lie with the respective shop operator or the respective provider of the online shop. It will be incumbent upon the respective shop operator to assess the permissibility of the data processing associated therewith and obtain any necessary consents.

### **II. THE USER’S RIGHTS**

If the legal prerequisites are met, you will be entitled to the following rights:

  1. The right to be informed of the data stored concerning you, the right to have this data corrected or deleted, the right to have the processing of this data restricted and the right to data portability. If you want to exercise any of these rights, please contact us via <https://www.wirecard.com/de/datenschutzbestimmungen/formular>.
  2. If you have consented to the use of your data, you may revoke this consent at any time.
  3. To revoke your consent or request information, please use our contact form or send your request by post or fax to Wirecard Technologies GmbH, Gleueler Straße 245-249, D – 50935 Cologne, fax: +49 (0) 332 269 090 20 (subject to the contractual rate agreed upon with your provider; no additional charges will be imposed by Wirecard).
  4. If you are of the opinion that the processing of your personal data is unlawful, you may at any time lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority. The relevant supervisory authority for data processing by Wirecard is the

**Bayerische Landesamt für Datenschutzaufsicht [Bavarian State Office for Data Protection Supervision]** **Office address** Promenade 27 (Schloss) 91522 Ansbach **Postal address** Postfach 606 91511 Ansbach

### **III. PASSING-ON OF DATA TO THIRD PARTIES**

We shall not pass on your personal data to third parties without your express consent. Excluded herefrom is the transmission of data to our external service providers, insofar as we need to involve these providers for the provision of our platform or for the implementation and handling of our contract, and such transmission is necessary for the purpose of performing the contract. We shall sometimes make use of external service providers in order to process your data for the purpose of performing the contract. These providers will be bound by our directives and be monitored by us.

### **IV. DURATION OF THE STORAGE OF DATA**

Your personal data will, subject to mandatory retention periods, official requirements and/or ongoing investigation proceedings, be deleted after the purpose of the data processing has been achieved.

### **V. DATA SECURITY**

We shall use technical and organisational security measures to protect your stored data against manipulation, loss, destruction and unauthorised access. To prevent unauthorised access to your data during your use of our online services, we shall use encryption techniques.

### **VI. COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA WHEN YOU USE OUR WEBSITE FOR OBTAINING INFORMATION**

When our website is used purely for obtaining information, i.e. if you do not log in or register, no personal data will be collected from you, except for data sent by your browser to enable you to visit the website. This data will encompass:

  *     * the IP addresses of the enquiring computers
    * the data volumes transferred
    * the name of the file retrieved
    * the date and time of the enquiry
    * the URL of the access.

Access to the online shop and any retrieval of a file deposited on our platform will be logged. Storage and usage will, on the basis of the relevant data protection laws, take place for the purposes of advertising, market research and tailored design, for statistical evaluations and for ensuring the security of your data and our platform.

### **VII. COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA WHEN YOU REGISTER AN ONLINE SHOP**

If you register and create a SUPR online shop or possibly use other services offered by us, your data provided during the configuration of the online shop and/or in the corresponding form will be collected and stored. This collection and processing of data will be necessary for performing the contract and will serve the creation, management and use of SUPR online shops.

### **VIII. COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL DATA WHEN YOU USE AN ONLINE SHOP**

In connection with the use of an online shop, personal data will be collected by the respective shop operator and processed for the purpose of performing the contract and, in particular, for handling your purchase order, delivering the goods and checking your credit standing and for handling the payment and any possible warranty cases. If you have any questions in this respect, please contact the relevant shop operator responsible for the data processing. In cases where a customer account is used in the SUPR network, see VII. If you have expressly consented to the receipt of newsletters from Wirecard Technologies GmbH, Wirecard Technologies GmbH will process your personal data in order to inform you of new developments or special offers on the SUPR platform. You may at any time unsubscribe from such newsletters and revoke your consent by using the “Newsletter unsubscribe” link within the Newsletter email or sending an e-mail to [unsubscribe@supr.com](mailto:unsubscribe@supr.com).

### **VII. COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL DATA WHEN YOU USE THE SUPR NETWORK**

As a customer, you have the possibility of registering an online shop for the SUPR network and setting up a customer account for yourself. If you set up a customer account in the SUPR network, your data provided in the registration form will be stored by Wirecard. Insofar as you have registered for the SUPR network and place a purchase order in an online shop as a registered SUPR network customer, your data will be passed on to the respective shop operator. For the purpose of performing the contract, it is necessary that your data provided in the registration form be stored and be passed on the respective shop operator. If you have any questions relating to the processing of this data in connection with use of the online shop, i.e. relating to the handling of your purchase order, the delivery of the goods, the checking of your credit standing or the handling of the payment or possible warranty cases, please contact the relevant shop operator responsible for this data processing.

### **VII. COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA IN CONNECTION WITH SUPR WIDGETS**

Widgets are modular components that shop operators and other providers can integrate into their websites, blogs, social media and apps. They contain the representation of a product, including a checkout module. If you have any questions, please contact the relevant shop operator, or other provider, responsible for the data processing.

### **XI. COOKIES**

  1. We use session ID cookies for storing your personal settings in order to ensure that your enquiries are quickly processed. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard drive and linked to the browser and send us certain information for identifying the user data. We use cookies in order to be able to identify you in the case of subsequent visits and to thus make our platform more user-friendly. In certain situations, it is elementary to keep information in the session cache. This applies to the log-in, for example. If the respective visitor successfully logs in, we shall store this state in his session. By means of the randomly generated key (session ID), we shall be able to correctly link the user within our system at any time.
  2. You may prevent the use of cookies yourself by setting your browser software accordingly. In this case, however, it may not be possible to fully use all features of this website.

### **XII. GOOGLE ANALYTICS**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer and enable your use of the website to be analysed. Normally, the information generated by such cookie concerning your use of this website will be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and be stored there. However, we have added the code “anonymizeIP” to Google Analytics on this website. As a result, your IP address will, within Member States of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area, be shortened by Google beforehand. Only in exceptional cases will your full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and be shortened there. Google will, on our behalf, use this information in order to evaluate your use of the website, put together reports on website activities and provide the website operator with other services relating to website and Internet usage. You can prevent the storage of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly. Please note, however, that you may then possibly be unable to fully use all features of this website. By downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the link (<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>), you can, furthermore, prevent data (including your IP address) generated by such cookie relating to your use of the website from being collected and transmitted to Google and being processed by Google. As an alternative to the browser add-on, especially in the case of browsers on mobile devices, you can, additionally, prevent the collection of data by Google Analytics by clicking on [this link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). As a result, an opt-out cookie that will prevent your data from being collected in future when you visit this website will be placed. This opt-out cookie will be valid only in this browser and only for our website and will be deposited on your device. If you delete the cookies in this browser, you will have to place the opt-out cookie again. We have concluded with Google an agreement on commissioned data processing. Further information on the terms of use and on data protection can be found at  <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html>[ ](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html)or at <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en-GB.>

### **XIII. FACEBOOK PLUGINS**

Additionally, we use on this website the social plugins (“plugins”) of the social network facebook.com, which is operated by Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”). These plugins include, for example, the so-called “Recommend” or “Like” button. The plugins are recognisable by one of the Facebook logos (white “f” on a blue tile, the word “Like” or a “thumbs up” sign) or are identifiable by means of the addition “Facebook social plugin”. A list of the Facebook social plugins, and their appearance, can be viewed here: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/> When you visit on this platform a website containing such plug-in, your browser will establish a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plug-in will be transmitted by Facebook directly to your browser and be integrated into the website by your browser. Therefore, we shall have no influence over the scope of the data collected by Facebook with the aid of this plugin and shall, therefore, inform you according to our level of knowledge. As a result of the integration of these plug-ins, Facebook will be informed that you have visited the corresponding website on our platform. If you are logged into Facebook at the same time, Facebook will be able to link your visit to your Facebook account. If you interact with the plugins, for example by clicking on the “Like” button or making a comment, the information concerned will be transmitted by your browser directly to Facebook and be stored there. Even if you are not a member of Facebook, it is nevertheless possible that Facebook may find out your IP address and store it. Information on the purpose and scope of the collection of data by Facebook, and on the further processing and use of data by Facebook, as well as on your rights in this connection and the setting options for the protection of your privacy can be gathered from Facebook’s Data Privacy Notices at: [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update.](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update) If you are a Facebook member and do not wish for Facebook to collect data concerning you via this platform and to combine this data with your membership data stored with Facebook, you will have to log off from Facebook before you visit our platform. Further settings and opt-outs relating to the use of data for advertising purposes are possible within the Facebook profile settings: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads> Further information on the purpose and scope of the collection of data by Facebook, and on the further use and processing of data by Facebook, as well as on your rights in this connection and the setting options for the protection of your privacy can be gathered from Facebook’s Data Privacy Notices.

### **XIV. OTHER PLUGINS**

  1. Our shops contain further plugins that lie within the sphere of responsibility of the respective provider (Google+, Pinterest, Twitter). Plugins may be executed when you visit the SUPR website. As a result, information concerning your visit may possibly be passed on to the respective provider of the plugins and be stored there. If you are registered or logged in with these providers, your visit to the SUPR shop may be linked to these providers. Once the plugin has been clicked on, third parties will be able to see this. This information will likewise be sent directly to the plugin provider and be stored there. You can prevent this identification by logging off from the plugin provider, and deleting the cookies if need be, before you visit the SUPR shop.
  2. We shall have no influence over the scope of the data collected and used by the respective provider with the aid of the plugin. Reference is hereby made to the provisions of the respective provider relating to the type, scope and purposes of the collection and use of personal data. It is often possible to also carry out at the provider itself settings relating to the handling of data and to obtain from there information on whether the data will possibly be processed outside of the EU.

**a. Google+** This offer is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. The Google+ button is recognisable by the “+1” sign. You can view here the Data Privacy Notices of Google+: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB> .  

**b. Twitter  ** Twitter is offered by the US company Twitter, Inc. (795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107). You can view here the Data Privacy Notices of Twitter: <https://twitter.com/privacy>.  

**c. Pinterest** Pinterest is offered by Pinterest, Inc., 808 Brannan St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. You can view here the Data Privacy Notices of Pinterest: <https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>.  

**d. Instagram** IInstagram is offered by Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA. You can view here the Data Privacy Notices of Instagram: <http://instagram.com/legal/privacy/>.  

**e. Tumblr** Instagram is offered by Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA. You can view here the Data Privacy Notices of Instagram: <https://www.tumblr.com/policy/en/privacy>.
